

Professional Summary

Business and Policy analyst with research and development experience. Relevant business management background and working knowledge of SQL, R, RDBMS, Python, Business financials, Microsoft office suite and UX Design fundamentals. Experienced in reviewing, updating and improving internal documentation, client-facing materials and project delivery methods.

Professional Experience

Improvtek Consulting- Business Analyst Project: Implementation of Mutual Guidewire Systems 07/2020 – 12/2020

- Analyzed over 20 system & functional specifications to meet project needs
- Facilitated Joint Application Design (JAD) sessions with business users and the development team to identify detailed business requirements.
- Identified and translated business needs into clearly defined requirements for insurance policy administration projects.
- Developed over 30 requirements documentation inclusive of user stories/ use cases, process flows, data flows and report mock-ups.
- Built strong relationships within the business units and support functions to understand the business needs.

Cooperation Canada- Policy and Research Analyst Project: Greening CSOs

05/2020 - 06/2020

- Analyzed the existing policy frameworks of over 50 civil society organizations in terms of operational greening and programming: while recommending green integration techniques
- Developed a repository of over 80 green tools and resources using Excel and tableau; to support Canadian civil society organizations in greening their operations
- Gathered a vast array of data and performed appropriate quantitative and qualitative analyses for report development

Email: oreoluwajoda@gmail.com Cell: 204-818-3395 Toronto, ON

Digital & Professional Skills

- SQL, RDBMS, HTML, Python, R, Visio, Tableau, UI/UX design fundamentals
- Loan risk assessment
- Business financials
- CRM, Microsoft Excel, Power point presentation & Word
- Change / Configuration Management
- Business Process Engineering
- Requirements Elicitation & Modelling
- Data Mapping & Modelling

Education

Advanced Digital & Professional Training Certificate Ted Rogers Management Institute, Ryerson University

Workshops: Design thinking, Business financials, Big data, SQL, SEO & Google analytics, Excel, HTML & CSS, UX Design fundamentals

University of Prince Edward Island Universidad Rey Juan Carlos Master in Global Affairs (Joint degree)

University of Manitoba Bachelor of Arts, Economics Minor: Management Synthesized data on climate action initiatives, climate financing and the green development fund towards the CSO project

Mogo Fin Tech- Loan Product Specialist Project: Implementation of Customer Relationship Management (CRM) tool (Salesforce)

04/2019-09/2019

- Improved the loan procurement process for clients by 80% through a combination of lean six sigma methodologies
- Utilized CRM, reference tools, and navigated the internal management system to meet client needs
- Evaluated applicants' financial status, including credit history, debt-to-income ratio, and appraisal reports, to determine recommendation for loan approval
- Communicated the brand's suite of loan products to over 70 clients per day and ensured the benefits were well understood
- Trained 10 new product specialists on the department's procedures and activities
- Received management and customer recognition for providing stellar loan procurement services

Health Canada- Project Ambassador Project: Know More Campaign

03/2019 - 07/2019

- Utilized technology and interactive elements in data collection, while monitoring and evaluating student preferences, metrics, and feedback for future advocacy programs
- Recommended program improvement techniques in design and delivery while improving participant attendance by 80%
- Liaised with management, support services, and administration in the implementation of new policies and service offering coordination

NGR Research Group- Business Analyst Project: QA Systems Upgrade

06/2017-06/2019

- Built and automated SAS codes to produce marketing reports and metrics dashboards
- Designed, developed and maintained KBI based analysis and reports on marketing activities and strategies (product acquisition, migration and retention)
- Worked within a variety of systems and tools to collect, query, manipulate and surface data
- Liaised with functional areas within the business to obtain/clarify information as required.
- Performed quality assurance on all data requests in order to ensure accuracy and integrity

Summary of Deliverables

- Business Impact Documentation,
- Project Charter, Project Plans,
- Project Reports, Business Cases,
- Business Requirement Document, Specification Requirement Document,
- User Stories, Risk Register, RAID logs, Business Needs Documentation,
- Requirement Workshop Agendas, Vision and Scope Documents, SOW, RFQ, RFPs
- Workflows and Activity diagrams, Test Strategy Documentation and, User Acceptance Testing Documentation
- Proof of Concept documentation, Risk/Change Management Plans
- RACI Matrices, Stakeholder Analysis document, Operational readiness Plan,
- SWOT Analysis, Requirement Traceability Matrices.

Certificates

Certified Associate in Project Management Training -

Master of Project Academy, New York (Certificate)

Certificate in Business Impact Analysis: Impaakt, Switzerland

Using Spreadsheets in Program Evaluation: Toronto

Fundamentals of Lean- Lean scape consultancy

British Council Certificate Course Ideas for a Better World: Leading Change Through Policymaking

European Union- Social Innovation Academy Certificate Course

National Collaborating Centre for Healthy Public Policy- Quebec Certificate: Framework for Analyzing Public Policies